Ah!? Another abandoned mine?!
啊！又一个废弃的矿井？！
Come, Starscream.
随我来 红蜘蛛
My liege, who could have foreseen that my alternative super-soldier experiment would encounter...
我的君王 谁能预料到我那超级战士实验会遭遇…
The technical difficulties?
技术性难题呢？
Resulting in the loss of the insecticon hive and over half our remaining troops!
赔上了全部昆虫大军和我们半数以上的部队吗？！
Forgive me, Master! My intentions were true!
请原谅我 主人！小人一片忠心 苍天可见！
Please! Please reconsider my termination!
求求您！小的再次给您磕头了！
Oh, Shockwave's offsite laboratory.
哦 原来这是震荡波的秘密实验室啊
Most impressive.
地方不错嘛
The Predacon clones have almost fully evolved
巨狰狞的克隆进展已经接近尾声
and will be combat-ready within three solar cycles.
预计将在三个太阳周期内完成战备
Well done! Shockwave.
干得好！震荡波
Knockout! I'm waiting.
击倒！我在等你
On my way. Lord Megatron!
马上就到 威震天陛下
Synthetic Energon... troops will be delivering my remaining supply to you.
合成能量…士兵们将会把剩下的库存送过来
I will determine its value after Lord Megatron's Predacon army is ready for deployment.
等威震天陛下的巨狰狞大军部署准备完毕 我会来评估其价值的
Unruly beast! You dare to roam freely without permission?
没规矩的畜生！你竟敢未经许可随处乱逛？
Aaah! Eh!
啊！呃！
Aaaah!!!
啊！！！
What!?
什么？！
Strike me again! And I will bury that rod in your spark.
再碰我一次！我就把那棍子插进你的火种里
I... I did not realize that the beast was capable of transformation.
我…我没想到野兽居然也能变形
Nor did I!
我也很意外呢！
I am no beast!
我不是野兽！
Aah!
啊！
The ability to transform is a fundamental part of Cybertronian biology.
变形能力是塞博特恩人的基本生理功能
We simply posses no evidence that the Predacon species ever reached that evolutionary stage,
但我们手中缺乏依据 去证明巨狰狞种群已进化至那个阶段
since they became extinct in the great cataclysm.
鉴于他们在大灾变中已经灭绝
And now we know... Ah...
现在我们知道了…啊…
So... the rumors are true.
如此说来…传言是真的
I would no longer be alone.
我也不再孤单了
And I see you've been keeping secrets.
原来你一直有所隐瞒啊
It was not my intention to deceive you, Lord Megatron.
我并非有意欺骗您 威震天陛下
I only recently became aware of my abilities.
我也是最近才发现自己的这种能力
All I remember of my beginning is hunting...
但我本身的记忆只有猎杀…
and battling...
…和战斗…
and the wounding of my pride.
…以及被人羞辱
Thus I'd begun to burn with questions...
于是我便产生了疑问…
Who am I?
我是谁？
Where did I come from?
我从哪里来？
The warship's data banks provide historical fact,
战舰上的数据库提供了一些史实依据
but, still, I possessed no memory of my own past,
但是对于我的过去 我依然一无所知
so I began to reconsider my place in the present...
于是我开始重新审视自己…
and wondered "could I be like the others?"
更想知道“我是否也像其他人一样？”
And now I know.
而现在我知道了
Yet you are unique, a miracle of science,
你的确是个独一无二的科学奇迹
cloned by Shockwave from cybernucleic acid,
是震荡波从提取的C.N.A.中克隆出来的
recovered from the remains of your mighty ancestors.
从你那强大的祖先遗物中重生的奇迹
Doctor, what is the current status of your Synthetic Energon experiments?
医生 你的合成能量研究目前进展如何？
Doing the best I can, Commander.
我一直在竭尽全力 指挥官
Given the lack of functional equipment at my disposal.
哪怕是我缺乏趁手的设备
You do realize that an alternative energy source may be essential to our survival?
你应该明白替代能源对我们的生存至关重要吧？
Heh... Believe me, Ultra Magnus.
呵…请相信我 通天晓
No one is more acutely aware of the stakes than I am.
没人能比我更了解这其中的利害关系
Uhm... Of cause.
呃…这是当然
Beast Hunters, may I ask why you are not currently scouting grid 305 for Predacon bones?
野兽猎人们 我想知道你们现在 为什么不在305区域搜索巨狰狞骸骨？
Because we just returned from surveying grids 301 to 304.
因为我们刚刚从301至304区域返回
To log our field reports, per your protocol, Commander Magnus, Sir.
以便根据您的规定去记录我们的实地报告 通天晓指挥官 长官
Soldier, I don't recall giving you permission to leave the base.
士兵 我不记得批准过你离开基地
Because you didn't, Sir.
你的确没批准 长官
Why are your hands smeared with coolant?
那为什么你的双手沾满冷却剂？
I... recalibrated your ship's engines.
我…我重新校准了你的飞船引擎
You can expect a 10% increase in vector thrust.
你可以体验下矢量推力提升一成的感受了
- Welcome back! - Optimus.
- 欢迎回家！ - 擎天柱！
- Good to see you! - It's good to have you back, Optimus.
- 见到你真高兴！ - 你回来真是太好了 擎天柱！
Decepticon activity is at a lull.
霸天虎没有活动迹象
I fear that Megatron may have collected the specimens he requires to...
因此 我担心威震天已经收齐了他想要的样本…
clone his army.
…来克隆他的军队
It is with deepest gratitude for my creation...
对您的再生之恩 我无以为报…
that I pledge undying obedience to you.
从今往后 定当效犬马之劳
My one true master.
我唯一的真正的主人
But with more of my species soon to stride among us,
而考虑到我的种群在队伍中不断快速壮大
I beg your permission to in turn, lead them,
我请求您能允许我 作为冲云霄
as Predaking.
…来领导他们
Your vision is boundless.
你倒是目光远大啊
A former beast may fully believe himself to be a loyal servant today,
这只曾经的野兽 或许眼下甘为奴仆
but trust me, the moment our royal highness...
但相信我 当有一天 我们这位王子殿下
realize that his army possesses greater might...
…发现他手下军队的战斗力已经能够…
than what currently remains of the Decepticons.
…凌驾于霸天虎残余部队之上时…
Evolution... will give way to revolution.
进化…必将导致变革
I am left with no choice...
我已别无选择…
but to eradicate the Predacon clones before they are provided the opportunity to eradicate us.
…只能在克隆巨狰狞造反之前根除他们
Lord Megatron, you're not saying you intend to pull the plug on Shockwave's beloved project Predacon?
威震天陛下 您不会是说要终止震荡波心爱的巨狰狞计划吧？
Your conclusion is most logical, my liege.
您的结论最为合乎逻辑 我的君王
But what happens if that fire-breathing brute discovers our treachery?
万一我们的背叛让那个喷火的兽人发觉了怎么办？
Why assume that we will be the ones to perform the deed?
干嘛非要认为我们得亲自动手呢？
After all, if the Predaking were to discover that, say, the Autobots were responsible for wiping out his comrades,
毕竟 比如说 如果冲云霄发现是汽车人干掉了他的战友的话
Our resident beast might, in turn, destroy our hated enemies for us...
我们手里的这只野兽说不定 会反过来消灭那些我们所痛恨的敌人…
or they him.
…或是被消灭
Ultra Magnus.
通天晓
Something has been troubling you.
你有烦心事了吧
I fear that my command style may be having a negative effect on unit morale.
我担心我的领导方式给部下的士气带来了负面影响
Your service is most welcome, old friend.
你是最忠于职守的 老朋友
But this is not the Elite Guard.
但这里毕竟不是精英卫队
Things have changed since the War for Cybertron.
塞博特恩之战后很多事情都发生了变化
And we must adapt to that change.
而我们必须适应这种变化
The members of Team Prime are not cogs in a machine.
领袖卫队的成员并不只是一部机器中的齿轮
They've grown into something greater than an army.
他们已经获得了一种比军人更重要的身份
They have become...
他们已经成为…
Optimus, our scanners have detected exposed energon.
擎天柱 扫描装置探测到了露天能量矿
With our reserves at a critical low,
鉴于我们的储备严重不足
we cannot afford not to investigate.
我们不能再放弃调查了
Decepticons, step away from the energon and surrender.
霸天虎们 放下能量 立即投降
Hia!
嘿呀！
Look at all that sweet fuel.
瞧瞧这些甜美的燃料
Stealth Team, transport our cargo back to base.
潜行小队 把货物运送回基地
Wreckers, reconnoiter the mine.
雷霆救援队 侦查矿脉
I've always wanted to roll with the Wreckers...
我一直想跟雷霆救援队一起行动…
Uh... Sir.
嗯…长官
No energon signals.
没有能量信号
And no additional security.
也没有加强戒备
Something doesn't smell right.
看起来很不对劲
Pair off.
两两一组
Well, this is one whole lot of ugly.
好吧 这是丑八怪展览馆么
Megatron's cloning operation seems further along than we anticipated.
看来威震天的克隆计划比我们预期的要更快
Starscream, the Autobots have arrived.
红蜘蛛 汽车人来了
You did not inform me that your plan was already in motion.
你没通知我 计划已经开始执行了
Only so the whole affair would appear less... staged.
假戏只有这样演才能…更乱真嘛
I have yet to purge my lab of sensitive materials.
我还没完全清除实验室的敏感数据
Then do not let me keep you, Shockwave. Over and out.
那你就快抓紧吧 震荡波 通话完毕
You scrapped him on purpose, didn't you?
你其实是想整他 是吧？
Soundwave, I require an immediate ground bridge.
声波 我需要紧急开启环陆桥
Lord Megatron, it seems Project Predacon has fallen into Autobot's hands.
威震天陛下 看来巨狰狞计划已经落入汽车人手里了
How was this possible!?
这怎么可能？！
Starscream, scramble your seeker and armada.
红蜘蛛 紧急出动你的追踪者大军
At once, my liege.
这就去 我的君王
No!
不！
If my brethren are imperiled, I will confront the enemy.
如果我的弟兄们受到威胁 就该由我去直面敌人
Permission to employ a grenade in a confined space, Sir?
请求批准在密闭空间扔颗手雷 长官？
If you and I are all that stand between these monsters and the natives of this planet,
如果只有我们两个能阻止 这些野兽屠戮这颗星球上的居民
then, by all means, blow these beasts back to the rust age.
那么 只管动手 把这些野兽轰成渣
Who's this guy?
这家伙是谁？
The very same who has previously allowed you to live,
就是之前曾放你一马的那个
But will not today.
不过这次可没门
He is the Pradecon.
他是那只巨狰狞
Wow! What was that?
哇喔！怎么回事？
What have you done to my brethren!?
你们对我的兄弟做了什么？！
What have you done!?
你们究竟做了什么？！
Yah!
呀！
Umh... Well then, let's dance!
呃…那好吧 我们耍一耍！
Woh!
喔！
Eh!
呃！
Ah!... Oh!...
啊！哦！
Aah!!
啊！！
Aah!!!
啊！！！
Uhm... eh...
嗯呃…
Eh!...
呃！
Eh... and here, I was just beginning to tolerate you.
唉…我刚刚开始能忍受你
It's been an honor serving beside you, soldier.
和你一起共事是我的荣幸 士兵
Prepare to perish.
准备受死吧
Awh!!!
啊！
What!? No!!!
什么？！不！！！
Oh...
噢…
Ratchet will take good care of you.
救护车会好好照顾你的
Magnus fought like a wrecker.
老通打架满有救援队范儿的
Optimus, when we spoke earlier.
擎天柱 我们之前谈到过
What could be greater than an army?
比军人更重要的身份是什么？
A human concept.
一个人类发明的词汇
one I have learned since coming to Earth...
这是我来到地球之后才懂得的…
Family.
家人
Do not despair, my Predaking.
不要绝望嘛 冲云霄
For I vow to you...
我向你保证…
that the Autobots will pay dearly for the outrage against your kind.
…汽车人会为对你族群的恶行付出沉重代价的
Shockwave, report.
震荡波 汇报
It is true, my liege. Project Predacon has been rendered null and void.
已经确认 我的君王 巨狰狞计划已毁于一旦
At least, I have been unable to recover any beast-forms.
我已经无法再复活任何野兽个体
However, there is something you must behold for yourself.
不过 有些东西需要您亲自过目
Heh! What is this?
哈！这又是什么东东？
Pure Cybertronian cybermatter,
纯正的塞博特恩网状物质
not unlike that which once existed upon our primeval home world.
与曾存在于我们家园的同类物质非常相似
Or that which engendered my citadel here on Earth.
也就是说 与我在地球建造堡垒的材料非常相似
The result of the explosion?
这是爆炸产生的？
Indeed, yet the cybernucleic acid alone cannot account for these... cyber-forms.
事实上 仅仅靠C.N.A.无法解释这种网状结构形成的原因
All possible logic points to the presence of one unexpected variable...
所有符合逻辑的推断都指向了一个意外加入的因素…
Synthetic Energon.
合成能量